<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<questions>
  <question id="question1">
    <questiontext>Describe the purpose of AJAX.  What advantage doe AJAX provide over a traditional HTML for submit?</questiontext>
    <answer id="answer1"></answer>
    <answertext>The purpose of AJAX is to exchange data with a server and update a web page without reloading the
                the whole page.  The advantage of AJAX over traditional HTML submit is that it seems more realtime in that you
                can validate a form as the user moves along and see errors quickly as opposed to waiting for the whole
                page to submit.  Also, things like search results can be added dynamically to a page instead of submitting
                and refreshing a whole page when it's not necessary.</answertext>
  </question>
  <question id="question2">
    <questiontext>Describe the role of JSON and XML with AJAX.</questiontext>
    <answer id="answer2"></answer>
    <answertext>The role of both JSON and XML with AJAX is to retrieve data from a web server and provide that
                data to a web page.  Both are self desribing, human readable, can be parsed and used by programming
                languages.  JSON however, seems to be faster and easier to use than XML.  
                Using XML is generally a 3 step process: 1. Fetch an XML document. 2. Use the XML DOM to loop thru the document. 
                3. Extract values and store into variables.  Using JSON is generally a 2 step process: 1. Fetch a JSON string.
                2. Parse the JSON string.</answertext>
  </question>
  <question id="question3">
    <questiontext>If you had to choose just one, which would you choose: XML or JSON? Why?</questiontext>
    <answer id="answer3"></answer>
    <answertext>I would definitely choose JSON over XML because JSON can easily become a Javascript object allowing
                access to data more readily.  JSON is shorter and has no end tag.  JSON can also use arrays and be
                parsed by standard Javascript functions.  XML has to be parsed with an XML parser which is more
                difficult.  I read one opinion, however, that said each format has its place.  For example, JSON is strictly a 
                better data exchange format and has no display capabilities.  Whereas XML is a better document exchange format 
                which can store some display capabilities.  So if you need a full document, like a medical record, with formatting
                included, XML just might be the better solution.</answertext>
  </question>
</questions>
